(THE YARNS)
The victim was around 70 years old.
The initial assumption is that the cause of death was likely due to physical assault.
There are bruises around the neck.
And the victim’s nails show
signs of scratching the perpetrator.
We’re getting closer to the truth.
It’s in here
So that’s mean this girl
witnessed the serial killer murdering the priest.
The CCTV footage collected from Miss Sookwan neighborhood
on the night of incident
DNA from the lollipop and the DNA of the killer
are 98% matched
You have no right to do this! What are you doing!
- Stop! You cannot go inside!
- I have to search your room, Sky.
How is this possible, inspector?
All the pictures here, they..
Exactly match with all cases.
Collect evidence
and arrest the suspect.
- Sky didn’t do it! How can you do this to her?!
- Ouch, it hurts!
Sky
I’ll let my friend here take you to the police station.
A police station is where people go to file complaints or arrest the bad people.
I didn’t have any complaints,
and I didn’t do anything wrong
Why do I have to go?
- Why do I have to go?
- Sky
We have to get something done.
Your mom is going with us too
Mom, you are going too?
Are you really going with me?
Yes, Sky. I’m going with you.
Ok, I’ll go.
Why do you bring your
police friends to search my room?
I don’t like this.
Really don’t like this at all.
Lun, these match all cases like copy-paste.
Hey, could it be that Sky knit these
yarns after seeing the news?
Then, the question is why does she have to hide it?
Believe it or not,
Sky's DNA showed up so clearly
that she is the one who did it.
Can an autistic kid really kill someone like this, sis?
But this case is not that normal.
That’s something we need to think about.
Miss Sookwan used to be a surgical nurse,
She could have taught Sky.
Is... Sky really a murderer?
If not
She might have multiple personality disorder,
like Lan suspected.
Multiple personality disorder?
Uh… Inspector
How is Sky doing now?
Why did you bring me here? Why did you lock me up?
I’m here to visit my daughter.
Hey Sky… Sky.
Sky
Sky, I’m here to see you.
-Sky
-Hello,
Could you open it for me please.
Sky
Thank you
Sky, do you want to decode something?
Decode?
Well,
I’m playing Sudoku
Do you wanna play?
Then, I’ll let you continue this, alright?
Miss Sookwan…
You should hurry and go get Sky’s medical certificate,
and her medical history
to confirm and prove that she is really autistic.
Then we can help proceed in separate confinement for Sky.
There will be a specialist
monitoring her during the confinement.
Right, I’ll go get them now.
Please take care of Sky
No worries
Doctor
Do you have any other ways
for us to get more information from Sky?
The main problem of this case
is the communication, inspector.
We need to find a way to help her express herself
From what I’ve been talking to Sky,
Does she have a multiple personality disorder?
It’s hard to say so.
it takes time to diagnose
we have to closely observe her behaviour and see whether she has other hidden personalities
By the way, you’ve mentioned
this disorder a few times already
Are you afraid that one of
Sky's personalities… is a murderer?
Excuse me for now.
-Thank you
-You’re welcome
Miss Sookwan
Is there anything I can help with? You arrive quite early.
No, nothing
Then, let’s meet around 1 pm.
I need to question you.
Sure
Excuse me
Uh…
Inspector
You've been with Sky for a while now
Do you really believe that
this simple-heart girl
who cannot even make a direct eye contact
could really kill someone?
I didn’t do it
I didn’t kill anyone
I didn’t kill the boxer
I didn’t kill the banker
didn’t kill P’Ya, didn’t kill Khun Anon
even though he hurted me.
didn’t kill the monk.
Didn’t kill Teacher Rapeephan. Didn’t kill the priest
Sky, Sky, Sky
If Sky didn’t kill them,
how do you know all this information?
It’s okay, Sky
I’ll show you … this photo
Sky, look at these yarns
Are you the one knitting these yarn?
Yes
I knitted these yarns myself
all by myself
why?
Why did you knit them into these pictures?
Where did you see them?
Um..
I don’t know
I don’t know… I don’t know
Well… that’s okay, Sky.
Sky
Have you worn this before?
This raincoat
Yes, I have. When it’s raining,
I wear this raincoat.
Well, if it’s raining you have to wear the raincoat.
No, Sky… I mean
Do you remember the last time you wear it? When was it, do you remember?
I don’t know where it is
I can’t remember
Alright, Sky
I’ll let you see the pictures of these people.
Can you tell me whether you know these people…
Do you know them?
This is Khun Anon, he hurted me.
This is my beautiful girl, P’Ya.
This is the bright-faced monk.
This is teacher Rapeephan
This…
This... is my friend’s mother
These two…
I
have seen…
never seen…
never seen …
have seen…
never seen…
Have you seen or never seen them, Sky?
I have seen them..
No… never seen them
Inspector…
I think she is not in a condition to give any statement.
-I think we should stop here.
-I never saw them.
Okay
Sky, Sky. It’s all done for today.
I’m not going to ask you anything else.
Sky, Sky
You don’t have to think about anything now.
Don’t have to answer anything too. It’s enough.
It’s enough, dear.
Miss Sookwan…
I just want to say that there are less than thirty-six hours left for us to keep Sky in custody.
So what now?
After this, we have to send her
to central prison as per the law.
The evidence I brought,
the doctor's note, won't help at all?
or how much money would it take?
Here’s the thing, Miss Sookwan…
The court will not grant bail for this case
because it's a serious crime
and it is one of the cases that get a lot of public attention
Mom, why are you crying? Did I do anything wrong?
No, you didn’t do anything wrong, dear.
It’s not your fault.
Then you shouldn’t cry, mom
Please don’t cry
don’t cry, okay?
When we get home, I’ll get you a lollipop.
Miss Sookwan
Miss Sookwan, you have to listen to me carefully.
After this
If you can think of anything,
or any information about Sky…
You have to tell me right away..
If you want to help Sky…
I miss Sergeant Moo.
Don’t know how he’s doing now.
They say he's getting much better. He should be able to return to work soon
Yeah, Lun
Do you get anything from investigating Miss Sookwan?
Is there anything suspicious?
Huh?
No, nothing
What about the syringe, the disinfectant,
and the bulk of rubber gloves?
This rubber gloves? I used to be a nurse.
I got into the habit of wearing rubber gloves
whenever I do cleaning.
Many autistic children are sensitive to fabrics or yarn.
So I have to make my daughter
wear rubber gloves when she knits
Don’t tell me…
that the disinfectant is for the same reason?
The disinfectant used in the surgical room, as well?
Yes, is that strange?
What about the syringes? What are you using it for?
The syringe?
- I use it to dye the yarn.
- Dyeing the yarn?
Sometimes, I have to dye the yarn myself for sales.
The yarn comes in blocks, but sometimes when I boil it with dye, the color doesn't absorb.
So I have to use a syringe, inject the dye into yarns to make sure it’s evenly colored.
And the surgical equipment?
Those surgical equipment belong
to Miss Sookwan’s father.
He used to be a surgical doctor
Then…
She’s off the hook.
But Sky… there’s no way she could get out of this.
Sky, are you hungry yet?
I brought something for you. Wow!
Who brought so much for Sky?
The police bought it for me.
The police bought all my favorites.
Sky
Are you bored? You’ve been here,
didn’t get to go anywhere.
The police told me to be patient.
So I have to be patient.
Excuse me, I have to transfer
the suspect to the central prison.
What... What’s going on?
I…I’m not going anywhere.
What are you doing… Why are you arresting me?
I’m not going
I didn’t do anything… I’m not going no no no
- Let go of me!!
- Sky
Please help me, officer
officer
please help me
Can you not cut my hair?
Don’t cut my hair, don’t cut my hair…
Can you please not cut my hair? Please.
Don’t cut my hair
So, the persone we caught doesn't have the murderer gene?
Yes, father
This is going to affect you a lot.
Your popularity will drop, and the chances of becoming the Prime Minister will be…
hard
Forget about this, Pitak.
If I didn't become one…
then I didn’t become one.
We have followed all the rules.
Our intentions have always been for the people
But the opposition will definitely
collaborate with the new government.
They will use this murder case…
to cancel the murderer gene law for sure.
That’s something I worry about.
The safety of the people will be gone.
But never mind.
Everyone has ups and downs.
Down
But soon, there will be ups.
You can go, I just called you to ask this.
Yes
Uh
By the way, are you staying at home tonight
or at the condo for tonight?
I'll be going back to the condo.
I haven't been there in a few days.
Then, I’ll leave now.
Wait
Congratulations.
I think you'll be getting a promotion soon.
I am Police General Sarun Wan-Omorn,
the Commissioner of the National Police Bureau.
would like to announce
to the public that...
We have arrested the serial killer from the yarn case.
Everything is proceeding as planned now.
There is no bail, as this is a severe case.
Are you sure this time it's not a scapegoat?
- Right?
- Right, are you sure?
-Definitely not.
-Are you sure?
Yes, this time we have solid evidence.
Has the criminal made a confession?
Not yet, but the statements are suspicious.
Does this criminal have killer genes
- Does he have it?
Yes
Everyone has ups and downs.
If down, there will soon be ups.
I heard that the criminal is an autistic
Is this true?
Have both killer genes and autistic?
- Is this true? Can you answer this?
- Is this true?
Does this criminal have both?
Yes
Wow, a crazy person...
and with killer genes too.
How did the police let him slip out like this?
He’s a hybrid killer for sure.
You’re insane. She’s an autistic kid, not a crazy person. Don’t exaggerating.
Haven’t you seen news from America?
An autistic kid brought a gun to school
and killed over twenty people.
This kind of person needs to be executed.
Believe me, she’ll get off claiming she’s crazy
Once this case is done, they’re going to push for a law to control people with mental illnesses.
Everyone’s equal
We don’t take this law
Ah, it’s getting out of hand now.
Inside and outside, who knows what’s real and what’s not?
Sis, sis do you know what?
the most terrifying person
is not the the autistic kid or those with killer gene
but human itself, that’s the scariest.
After the police press conference...
Seems like your popularity is rising up again.
even better actually.
Now that the murderer is autistic.
- Is it Lun?
- Yes.
Tell him I’m not here
Yes sir
If I ever become prime minister...
I promise...
I’ll wipe out all those scumbags
Inspector…
You've been with Sky for a while now
Do you really believe that
this simple-heart girl
who cannot even make a direct eye contact
could really kill someone?
Do you like the sky, Sky?
Yes.
I like the sky.
s k y that means Sky
If you like that…
I’ll take the photo for you?
Will you take a photo for me?
Um
Sky
Look at the camera.
I didn’t look at you
On the police's side, they might have solid evidence,
but have you ever tried thinking
from another perspective, Inspector?
Or do you really believe in the evidence
that make you convinced
Sky is really the killer?
I won’t ask for anything else except
please finish reading this book.
What is harder
finding the answer?
or prove the answer people have given you
whether it is correct or not?
Wait, what did you ask, Lun?
I said…
What is harder
between finding the answer
or prove that that answer is…
correct or not
What do you think, Sergeant?
I think finding the answer
I think proving it is harder
I also think proving.
Great, then shall we start?
Start proving whether Sky's the real murderer.
What
that...
how is this related?
If the serial murders are an equation,
then we’ll prove that finding the killer
and proving if that killer is the real one
What's harder or easier?
Are you saying you don’t believe that
Sky isn’t the real murderer?
That’s possible, isn’t it?
You’re mixing personal feelings with the case now
How?
Where am I talking about personal stuff?
I am talking about the serial killer.
Lun, how many people have we lost before
catching the real serial killer?
not counting the death of P'Rapee, Sergeant moo’s wife.
And now you are saying you don’t believe that
Sky is the real killer?
If you didn’t like that girl,
are you really going to doubt her?
That’s what I also thought, Inspector.
I agree with her, Inspector
The evidence is this solid,
- There shouldn’t be anything wrong
- Didn’t you say that autistic people don’t lie?
We have investigated Sky several times, asking her whether she killed these people or not.
and she said no
- It might still not be true, right?
- Don’t be so naive, Lun
Everything has exceptions.
You can’t prove the truth with some
sharp quotes from books, okay?
You just said earlier that proving is harder.
Yes
But we can prove the answer to this equation from all the evidence we have.
Videos from the victim’s mobile phone, images from the CCTV showing Sky climbing out of the house.
Sky’s yarn and the murderer also exactly the same
Not to mention the mysterious phrase that only Sky can solve.
The images of the victims'
deaths hidden under Sky’s bed.
An
In that clip, we can’t clearly see the person’s face
It’s almost impossible to see it. Another thing is that the raincoat is just similar. It could have been a coincidence.
- That’s why we need to prove.
- What proves that this equation is correct is the DNA.
How did Sky’s DNA end up under
the victim’s fingernails, huh?
if she didn’t fight with the victim, think about it
-what about the motive?
-Oh, come on.
Sky is autistic
She could be doing something without thinking.
or she might have multiple personality disorder, just like you suspect, Lan.
If Sky is both autistic and has multiple personalities.
I think she is just too unlucky.
Hey, Lan.
Sis, calm down. Calm down
- Calm down
- Let me tell you something.
Since I’ve been with Sky from the start,
there’s never been a moment when Sky showed any aggression, not even once.
No
not even in her eyes.
And if what you’re saying is true...
If Sky really does have multiple personalities,
When Sky was captured by the fake killer, why didn’t Sky show another personality?
Who knows?
The Sky who blinked and gave the room number
and the Sky who sent the SOS signal
could be two different people.
The doctor already said that
The connection between these
- personalities doesn’t link together.
-Oh, stop it, Lan. Stop. Enough
stop making excuses.
If you want to make excuses, go ahead and prove this answer on your own.
I’m not doing it anymore.
what, sis come on..
What do you think?
uh..
well, inspector…
we should let this matter go through the process.
Hey, is that the next room is the room of the serial killer with the mental illness in the news
What the fuck, that’s scary… This is fucking bad…
Why do we have to be locked up with her?
What if she kills us too?
I’m scared.
Yeah, yeah, right.
Sky Supharat, you have a visit from your relative.
Can you hear? Your relative is visiting.
Your mom here
Go and sit nicely
I won’t sit
No sitting or no visiting, you choose.
you only have 15 minutes.
hurry up
Sky
How are you, Sky?
It’s me
Pilanthorn
Your police friend..
You are not my friend…
not my friend anymore…
you locked me up…
you are the one who locked me up here.
you let people tie my hands and cut my hair.
you didn’t help me
you lied to me
I hate you, I hate you.
Lun
Stop it, Lun. No matter what, Sky can’t get out of this
Lun, what do you think you are doing?
-Sky is a serial killer!
-An
If you want to believe that…
Then go on…
But you can’t change my mind.
It’s not because I want to believe it or not, Lan.
I don’t want to believe it either that Sky is a serial killer.
Other evidence could have been
falsified or mistaken, Lan…
But not DNA…
Lun..
-Come out!
-Come out here, you killer!!
- Come out!
- What’s this?
- You killed my kid.
You killed my wife… You come out!!
Come out!
What are you doing at my house?!
What’s this? I’ll report this to the police.
What’s going on here?
This is the mother of the killer who killed my child!
How did you raise your child to be a killer?
-how did you raise her like that?
-Report to the police?
- Go ahead!
- Hey listen!
My child is autistic, not a murderer.
If she was a murderer and you
knew she was a murderer,
- why don’t you kill her from the start?
- right!
-why let she kill my wife?
-No
-Why let her!
-you bitch!
- Did you see how the news reported it?
- Why are you talking nicely to her!
Just do it already, why talk nicely to her?
-Fuck off!
-Listen
- No
- Why kill my wife! why!
- You killed my wife!
- Stop, Stop!
My daughter is not a killer!
Drink some water first.
Are you hurt anywhere, sir?
No, I’m alright..
Thank you for helping me… and for telling those to go away.
you don’t have to thank me
because I came here to do what they did.
Even though I hate you both so much,
but as a police officer,
I can let you be mistreated like this.
because you are not a murderer.
or even if you are,
you shouldn't be treated like this…
because criminals must be punished by law.
But Sky is not a murderer.
Please help Sky…
- Please… please help Sky.
- I can’t help you with anything.
Wrongdoers must be punished for what they did.
But Sky didn’t do anything…
She is not a murderer.
Please help Sky…please.
Then you have to find evidence
that proves your daughter didn’t do it.
You didn’t help me
You lied to me
you… I hate you…
If you want to tell me to stop,
then you should go back, An…
I’m not changing my mind.
It’s me, inspector.
How are you?
Getting better?
Yes, I heard you have caught the murderer.. so I came back to continue working.
Do you…
You also believe...
that Sky is the one who did it…
I don’t believe in anything…
before you can prove
who is the real murderer who killed Raphee.
You think like me, do you?
No, sir
I have been a police officer for so long..
I have seen everything…
catching scapegoats, substitutes, or the real culprits.
but this time…
I want a real culprit.
only the real one.
Great
I’ll try my best to prove whether…
Sky
is a real murderer or not…
for Raphee
I’ll help you, inspector…
Come on, sis. That’s enough…
Stop drinking now.
If you are not helping then just shut up.
This is more useful than you!
Fine, go ahead… do whatever you want.
I…
I came to be a forensic doctor,
ven with my brain… I can be any kind of doctor anywhere and get a lot more than I earn now.
I didn't have to stay here, surrounded by corpses.
But I choose to do so…
because I want to work with Lun…
I can just hope…
hope that one day…
He would see my feelings.
but, but what now…
I understand, sis…
When we like someone,
but they don't like us…
how does that feel…
Why does Lan have to like that autistic kid?
That's too much…
How are they even suited for each other?
What is the meaning of being suited for each other, sis?
There are millions of couples in this world.
Some people like each other for their similarities.
Like chopsticks…
They’re the same,
but one part that is longer than the other.
And the spoon and fork,
some love each other for their differences.
not the same
but get along well…
If you're drunk and talking like this, just shut up.
Isn’t it true, sis?
Who in the world has rice with spoon and spoon?
If you spoon…
Can I be your fork?
Hey…Sis!
Sis
you're just asleep?
when I was holding my courage and talking to you…
Let’s go… let’s go home.
sis
sis, go home
wake up
Let's go home.
Let’s go home, I’ll take you home
Check, please
Come on, let’s go
hurry! Come on, sis, let’s go home!
Inspector… Why are you decoding that
If you want to prove that Sky is not a murderer…
Because if Sky is not a murderer.
that’s mean there will be more people being murdered.
because I want to know who the murderer is.
and even if that person is Sky…
I would like to know who she will murder…
and why…
Inspector…
look at this!
Look at this video here.
At first, when the murderer burned the victim, there was nothing on the top of the bin.
but when the murderer is dead
The murderer came back and put
the yarn and stick on the cover.
Do these two things have something to do with each other?
Miss Sookwan…
Is there something you need?
There is something about Sky I need to tell you.
I used to think that Sky was a murderer.
what!
you heard it right
I used to think that Sky was a murderer.
Two months ago, I saw Sky’s knitted yarn.
It looked scary and strange.
She never knitted something like that before…
The body of a middle-aged woman was found, later identified as Mrs. Nattha Janbriwan
an employee of a bank.
She died from a needle being inserted into her vein
and the needle flowed into the bloodstream, reaching her heart, causing death.
as you know…
The knitted yarn exactly tells
the cause of death for each victim.
whether the gender or the method of killing.
I was really shocked.
I didn’t know how Sky knew all about this…
- If she wasn’t…
- I get it now…
I now understand why you didn’t want
us to get involved with Sky at first.
But… how can you be sure that
Sky didn’t knit those yarns?
- after seeing the news…
- At first, I hoped it would be like that.
until one afternoon…
Sky… where are you going… we are going to the temple.. Sky…
- I have to go.. have to go… I have to go..
- where.. go where..
Sky, where are you going…
- tell me where are you going…
- Sky
- I have to go.. I have to go…
- Go where? Sky, where?
- Sky, don’t be like this.. Tell me, what is going on…
- I have to go
Dead again… I have to go…
- must die.. I have to go…
- who dead? who?
I am going… must die….
- Sky, who’s dead
- I am going… must die….
- must die
- Tell me, Sky. Please don’t be like this…
Please don’t be like this…
Sky, what’s wrong…
- Please don’t be like this…
- Someone’s dead again, someone’s dead again.
dead again
What should I do…
- Someone’s dead again, someone’s dead again.
- Sky, don’t be like this…
- Someone’s dead again, dead again
- Who’s dead?
dead again, dead again.
Sky, who’s dead?
-Sky, tell me
-Dead
- Someone’s dead again, dead, dead
- Sky, who’s dead? Sky…
- Sky, where are you going… Sky
- dead again
Who’s dead…
Sky, who’s dead… Sky, don’t be like this.
- dead again, dead again.
- Sky, what are you doing…
- dead again
- Sky
I’m worried, Sky. Why is this happening?
What are you doing?
What are you knitting?
What are you doing? Sky
You are telling me that Sky knew about every death
before it happened?
I don’t know too, I didn’t know Sky would be like that.
This isn’t something an autistic person would do.
It’s like... it’s like a different person
Or it’s another personality of Sky…
But that day, you went to the temple with Sky?
Every time Sky finishes knitting, Sky becomes a completely different person.
She agree to go to the temple?
The day that the monk died…
Sky was with me..
That’s when I believe she is not a murderer.
That’s mean Sky would left the house
before the victim died, right?
I don’t know too, we are in different room.
I had told Sky to sleep in my room.
But she didn’t want to
She would do things in her own way.
If that's the case, let’s do it this way, Miss Sookwan.
From all 7 cases that happened,
how many times were you with Sky?
Just one.
Then... Can I be a witness for Sky?
Do you have any witnesses
who can confirm your identity, Mr. Sookwan?
or evidence that confirms you were with Sky?
It could be a photo, a video, or a CCTV recording.
No, I don’t have
I’m a low tech person…
I don’t know anything, and cannot do anything…
I can only tie a bell to the door.
Every time Sky goes somewhere,
I will know, I can hear it.
If that’s the case,
I think it will be very difficult.
And especially when it’s a statement
from the mother of the murderer,
the court will probably not accept it.
But at least I’m one person...
who believe that Sky didn’t kill the monk.
Let me ask one more question.
Why didn’t you destroy those knitting?
Sky, give them to me. I’ll burn all of them.
You cannot burn them. This is mine. It’s mine!
- You cannot burn them!
- Sky, we can’t keep it here!
- I’ll keep it! I’ll keep it
- No, Sky, you can’t
- I’ll keep it
- Sky
Sky, you have to hide it under your bed like this.
Yes, hide it here, hide it here
You won’t burn my stuff…
But I know that one day, someone will find it.
Thank you so much, Miss Sookwan, for trusting me.
So now that you know…
Will you help Sky?
Do you believe her like I do?
that she is not a murderer…
I have to say that from everything you’ve told me,
it’s really hard to believe.
since you are Sky’s mother and the only one who saw that,
It's really difficult. As I said,
it’s hard for the court to believe.
But Sky is not a murderer.
Help help Sky…
Please, inspector…
You looks very confident that Sky is not the murderer.
I’m not so sure either…
I don’t even know if what I think is right or wrong.
But what I’m sure of is that I want to use all the remaining time to prove that we didn’t catch the wrong person.
- CPNS
- Yes, sir
Do you think…
the yarn and the stick connected in any way?
I don’t see any connection
the yarn and the stick
unless they were physically connected somehow.
Like really connect them together.
Physically connected?
Yes
- Yes, Yes!
- What?
You hold this!
Physically connected?
Connected.
- Hold it tight
- Yes sir..
cute cmu kmitl
Name of the university?
University? Is the murder going to kill the teacher again?
It’s all possible.
University, teachers, students.
then, what university?
here are a lot of universities in Bangkok
These are all seven places that the murderer occurred.
you can see that it’s all in the same area.
And the murderer kills
the victim between home and work.
from my assumption…
the next incident will probably happen in this area.
If your assumption is correct…
There is a university here, right here.
and if i’m not wrong.
There should be an abandoned factory around here too.
- Let’s go, Sergeant. Let’s check it out.
- Yes
Inspector…
We’ve searched this area, there’s nothing suspicious.
I think we may not find anything more.
Sergeant,
Check the HT warehouse again before we go back
- We checked that warehouse earlier
- The murder might just arrive
Inspector…
You seem to really like that kid.
Maybe what An said is true, that I may have mixed personal feelings with work.
So you want to prove that she is not a murderer.
You don’t have to worry.
Even if the court sentences the maximum penalty tomorrow, there’s still time to appeal,
and the court will reduce
the sentence because Sky is autistic.
- Let’s go
- Yes sir…
as the plaintiff’s evidence is
stronger than the defendant’s evidence.
The facts indicate that the defendant
is guilty under the Penal Code
Section 289 (4), Premeditated murder.
Section 289 (5)
Murder through torture
or acts of cruelty shall be punished with…
Your honour… May I…
The court is currently rendering its verdict…